Gyampoh Obiri Alexander (KITCO), PMB, Kibi

Telephone: +233 (0) 244710415; 0264710415

E-mail: ao.gyampoh@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I have a good communication and interpersonal skills, high level of commitment on the job, team player's attitude, personal creative initiative abilities and safety conscious attitude, these and others have been my track record to successfully, professional and proficiently teach and assess learners to help them to graduate as professionally competent teachers.

Some other areas of specialization are Chemistry, Physics, Biology, Methods of teaching Science, Energy and Power distribution (Physics), Pollution Control, Microbiology, Occupational Health and Safety, Environmental Chemistry, Policy analysis etc.

PERSONAL DATA

Date of birth: 23rd June, 1979 Place of birth: Agona Swedru. Home Town: Akim Asuoso Nationality: Ghanaian

Gender: Male

Marital status: Married

Considerable Work capabilities particularly in Tutoring include the following:

- Organizes and prepare scheme of work and lesson plan according to subjects and topics assigned to me.
- Teach subjects and topics assigned to me according to the course outline.
- Prepare practical schedules according to my course outline for my learners.
- Organizes practical lessons to the level of my learners.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- ♣ Kibi Presbyterian College of Education, Kibi
- ♣ Head of Science Department, (2014-2018)
- **♣** Science –Integrated Science, (2018)
- **♣** Assistant supported teaching coordinator, (2018 -)
- ♣ Project work coordinator, (2018 -)
- ♣ Physics, Biology and Chemistry Tutor, (2007)
- **↓** Church of Christ campus ministry Patron. (2008 -)
- ♣ Science teacher at Breman Brakwa meth. JHS (2000-2002)
- ♣ Chemistry teacher at Nana Khadijah Islamic sec. sch.- Agona Swedru (2006-2007)

1

October 2007 to date:

(Course Tutor for the following courses FDC 114C, FDC 114 CP, FDC 114, FDC 224 M & FDC 224, FDC 224P & FDC224PP, FDC 224C and FDC 224CP)

Key Responsibilities include the following:

- Prepare weekly scheme of work for my courses in the specific semester.
- Prepare practical schedules for my courses in the specific semester.
- Prepare lesson note/outline for my courses in the specific semester.
- Professionally teach my students/ learners to understand the under-lining concepts of my courses.
- Prepare assessment blue prints to follow to write quiz questions.
- Mark and score assignments and quizzes.
- Prepare continuous assessment professionally.
- Organize practical lessons and maintain the Laboratory.
- Attend regular campus church meetings

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Successfully taught over 780 students/learners to pass their final examinations.
- Able to submit quiz questions and marking scheme on time
- Able to give enough assignment, mark and record on time.
- Able to prepare continuous assessment and submit on time.
- Able to manage the Department well

COMPUTER INTELLIGENCE

Have Skills in Computer Software's such as the under listed.

Microsoft Word, Microsoft Power Point, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, Internet Applications, Coral draw

EDUCATION

- Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST) 2013. **Msc. Environmental Science (Environmental Chemistry).** (With a research interest in environmental auditing & Occupational Health and Safety)
- Institute of commercial management ICM-Blue Alliance. Certificate in managing Occupational Health and Safety. (2012)
- University of Education, Winneba. (2003-2007)
 Bachelor of Science Education (Chemistry Option)
- Sehwi Wiawso College of Education (Teachers Certificate A), 2000

Workshops attended

Date	Organizer	Workshop	Place
27th – 30th May,	T-TEL	NTS and Teaching	ABETICOE
2019		Practice	
29th -31st January,	T-TEL	Conduct and	Blue royal hotel,
2019		supervision Mf new	larteh
		4yr curriculum for	
		COEs	
5th -8th December,	Varkey foundation	Pedagogical methods	NODA hotel,
2018		of Teaching	Kumasi
	T-TEL and	Institutional	Tamale, Asanti
	MENTEE	strengthening,	Mampong, Kibi
	COLLEGES	gender and	
	(Facilitator)	mentoring of the 6	
		newly absorbed	
		COEs	
14 th - 18 th May, 2018	T-TEL	Orientation for new	Sunyani- Sheila
		colleges of education	executive hotel
		and their mentors	
3 rd – 4 th May, 2018	T-TEL	Mobilizing local	Koforidua- Eastern
		resources and	Premier hotel
		partnerships to	
		improve the	
		professional	
		preparation of pre-	
		service teachers in	
		Ghana's colleges of	
		education	
23 rd – 25 th April,	T-TEL	Refresher course on	Koforidua- Capital
2017		financial and	View hotel
		narrative reporting	
8 th – 12 th August,	T-TEL	Cluster mentor, lead	Ho - Volta hotel
2016		mentor, GEO and	
		CS training	
29th May, 2018	KIBICOE	Peer mentoring	Takoradi – Holy
		strategies	Child college of
			education

Some major courses offered:

- Environmental Chemistry, Analytical Chemistry, Organic Chemistry, Inorganic Chemistry, Biology, Methods of Teaching Science, Energy and Power Distribution, Psychology of Human Development, etc
- Blue Alliance -ICM: essentials of occupational health and safety, Emergency procedures, control of hazardous substances etc

SSSCE (Oda Senior High School-ODASCO)

• Major Elective subjects offered.

Physics, Chemistry, Biology

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT COURSES/ TRAINING OFFERED.

- 1. Blue Alliance- ICM (UK) Certificate in health and safety management.
- 2. KNUST (Kumasi); Msc Environmental Science
- 3. University of Education, Winneba (Bed. Science)
- 4. Sehwi Wiawso College of Education (Teachers Certificate A)
- 5. Ghana Red Cross Society. Standard First Aid Certificate.
- **6.** DVLA Have a light duty driving license "B"

LEADERSHIP SKILLS/ POSITIONS HELD AT THE UNIVERSITY

•SRC Audi Board Secretary (2005-2006 academic year)

Successfully edited and produced and audited accounts for the General Assembly

- •Chairman of the Publicity Committee during the 2006 SRC Week Celebration
- •General Assembly Member Unified SRC of UEW

HOBBIES

Reading, listening to soul inspiring music

REFEREES

1. Dr. Ter-Larbi

Lecturer

Department of Theoretical and Applied Biology

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology –Kumasi (KNUST)

Mobile: 0244759040, 0261173549, 0270759040, 0233759040

2. Rev. Charles Fosu Ayarkwah

Principal

Presbyterian College of Education, Kibi

Mobile: +233 (0) 244210503

3. Rev. Dr. Bernard Kofi Adinkrah

Acting College Secretary
Presbyterian college of education, kibi

Mobile: 024483621

Signature:	Date: